# BAILEY WATSON

## **SUMMARY**

As a recent Psychology graduate at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill (UNC-CH), I am searching for valuable experience in any field. With my experience as an academic tutor and working in the education system, I am inspired to utilize my ability in relaying information and catering to the needs of others

## **SKILLS**

#### TEACHING AND EDUCATION SKILLS

Strong critical thinking skills.

Clear and compelling communicator when working in teams

Ability to streamline and relay complex concepts.

Proactively engaging with students and catering to their individual needs

Proven teaching, guidance, and counseling skills

Attention to detail and organizing materials for others to follow

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Creating responsive, inclusive, and accessible websites using HTML, CSS, and user interface (UI) design.

Ability to work independently and be creative when help is not accessible

Experience in running basic statistical analyses using R.

Ability to organize and manage multiple projects

Interpreting data and conducting statistical and item analysis using R and SPSS.

Strong visualization skills.

Developing and maintaining client relations within a business

Conducting professional business communication during project evaluations

Proficient in Microsoft Excel (able to sort and analyze data, filter data, use formulas, create graphs and data tables)

# **EXPERIENCE**

Aug. 2021 - Current Central Carolina Community College, Virtual Academic Tutor, Pittsboro, NC

Subjects Tutored: Pre-calculus, Calculus, College Algebra, Biology, Chemistry, Trigonometry, and Psychology.
 Built a studying/school work routine for students, demonstrated more effective and efficient studying strategies, taught and elaborated on course material, and constructed final exam studying materials for students.

Access Paving and Construction, Seasonal Worker (Paving Crew), Chapel Hill, NC June 2022 - Aug. 2022

Aided with on-site jobs and moving equipment.
 Worked with paving crew, refueled equipment, met and discussed paving/grading projects with potential clients, kept trucks fueled, and filled water and diesel tanks in company trucks.

Woods Charter School, Classroom Facilitator for Middle School Math. Chapel Hill, NC Mar. 2021 - June 2021

June 2017 - Aug. 2021

\*\*Modifie School, and Mith (Grades 5-5) Classroom Facilitation Grade Math.

\*\*Courses Taught 5-th Grade Math, 7th Grade Math, and 8th Grade Math.

\*\*Courses Taught 5-th Grade Math, 7th Grade Math, and 8th Grade Math.

\*\*Proctored EOG syEOC's, conducted EOG/EOC review sessions, prepared lessons that were inclusive for in-person as well as online learners (who joined class via Google Meets), and maintained COVID-19 protocols

Woodcroft Swim & Tennis Club. Lifeguard/Camp Counselor/Swim Lesson Instructor/Snack Bar Attendant. Durham. NC

• CPRIACED/rist Aid Certified

• Pool Responsibilities: Lifequard and ensure the safety of all patrons, cleaned the bathrooms/pool/pool deck.

• Camp Responsibilities: Constructed and facilitated various learning activities, taking campers to the pool and ensuring their safety as a trained lifeguard, facilitated outdoor games and activities, and instructed tennis and soccer lessons.

• Swim Lesson Responsibilities: Constructed and facilitated various learning activities, taking campers to the pool and ensuring their safety as a trained lifeguard, facilitated outdoor games and activities, and instructed tennis and soccer lessons.

• Swim Lesson Responsibilities: Maintained professional customer service with parents.

• Customer Service/Miscellaneous Responsibilities: Maintained professional customer service with patrons, charged membership accounts/credit cards, and managed snack bar inventory/bookkeeping.

# **PROJECTS**

Personal Tutoring Website May 2022 - Current

To showcase my HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and UI design skills, I decided to develop a website that advertises my personal tutoring. No template was used and the entire website has been developed from scratch. The website is targeted at primarily high school and collegiate students, but is also for parents seeking personable and local online tutoring for their children.

in accordance with my lithro to Web Design/Development course, I was tasked with creating a website for a student led organization at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill titled "Active Minds at Carolina". Active Minds focuses on mental health and connects students with mental health resources in the community. I developed a tally responsive user interface (UII) design and coordinated with an organization representative to meet their website needs. Additionally, I was a lead developer in providing the overall code and formatting of the website using HTML and CSS. I developed the overall site's layout (i.e., novigation bar and footed), responsive user to have page as well as the contact for UNIX-CH students page.

# **EDUCATION**

Central Carolina Community College Associate of Science University Transfer 2021 Aug. 2019 - May 2021

### **AWARDS**

Received A's and B's in all semester courses

Dean's List and Good Academic Standing, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

Dean's List and Good Academic Standing, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

Dean's List and Good Academic Standing, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

Received A's in all Associate in Science courses and graduated with a 4.0.

Received A's in all Psychology courses

Received all A's and completed at least 12 credit hours

Academic Excellence Award for Achievement and Excellence in Psychology, Central Carolina Com

President's List for Fall and Spring Semester (2020 and 2021), Central Carolina Community College